Hello, and welcome to Lesson 22 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
大家好，欢迎来到本次与沃尔夫兰大学合作的微积分入门第22课
The topic for this lesson is antiderivatives.
本节课的课题是反函数
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
先来简单介绍一下本课的内容
So far, we have been talking about derivatives of functions.
到目前为止 我们一直在讨论函数的导数
For example, the derivative of 3x with respect to x is just 3.
例如 3x 相对于 x 的导数只是 3
Now let’s say you want to go backward.
现在假设你想往回想
You want to find a function whose derivative is 3.
你想找一个导数为 3 的函数
Now of course in this case, you already know that 3x is the answer, or it is an answer,
现在当然在这种情况下 你已经知道 3x 是答案 或者说它是一个答案
but in this lesson, we’ll go over that for many different kinds of functions.
但在这节课中 我们将针对许多不同类型的函数进行讲解
This idea of going back has many applications.
这种倒过来回想的方法有很多应用
For example, if you’re given the particle’s velocity function in a problem,
例如 如果在一道题中给你粒子的速度函数
you could go out and work out the position of a particle.
你可以出去计算出粒子的位置
That’s the main theme for today,
这就是今天的主旋律
to try and go backward and figure out a function whose derivative is a given expression.
试着往回想 找出一个函数 其导数是一个给定的表达式
That’s the topic of antiderivatives.
这就是反函数的话题
The function with a given derivative f is called the antiderivative of f.
具有给定导数 f 的函数称为 f 的反导数
Now let’s take f equal to x.
现在我们取 f 等于 x
The question is what is its antiderivative?
问题是它的反函数是什么
Then what you could do is you could actually use the power rule, but you do it in reverse.
那么你可以做的是 你实际上可以使用权力规则 但你要反过来做
You have x^2, so increase the exponent by one to get the x^2,
你有 x^2 所以将指数增加一 得到x^2
and then you would divide by the new exponent, so the answer is x^2/2.
然后除以新的指数 所以答案是 x^2/2
But that’s only one possible answer you’ll see soon.
但这只是一个可能的答案 你很快就会看到
Let’s confirm with D, and you’ll see that the derivative of x^2/2 is indeed x.
我们用D来证实 你会发现 x^2/2 的导数确实是 x
We have found an antiderivative of x, and that’s x^2/2.
我们已经找到了 x 的反导数 那就是x^2/2
Here’s a plot of x and the antiderivative.
这是一个 x 的图和反导数
Okay. This is the function, and that’s the antiderivative we found out.
好吧 这就是函数 这就是我们发现的反导数
Now we said over here that x^2/2 is an antiderivative of x,
现在我们在这里说过 x^2/2 是 x 的反导数。
and that’s because every function has more than one antiderivative.
那是因为每个函数都有一个以上的反导数
For example, in our case,  x^2/2 + 1 is also an antiderivative.
例如 在我们的情况下 x^2/2+1 也是一个反求式
In general, if you have one antiderivative,
一般来说 如果你有一个反导数
you have many more by simply adding arbitrary constants.
通过简单地添加任意常数 你可以拥有更多的常数
This expression over here gives you a family of antiderivatives.
这边的表达方式给了你一个反衍生品的家族
Here’s a plot to show that for the function we just talked about, the function x:
下面用一张图来说明 对于我们刚才讲的函数 x
you have x over here, the function, and all those curves are antiderivatives for x.
你有x在这里 这个函数 所有这些曲线都是x的反导数
Notice that each of them is simply a vertical shift of x^2/2 either up or down.
请注意它们中的每一个都只是 x^2/2 向上或向下的垂直移动。
Okay. Some rules for antiderivatives.
好吧 说一些关于反导数的规则。
The antiderivative of a sum is the sum of the antiderivatives.
一些式子和的反导数是反导数的和
For example, if you want to work out the antiderivative of x^2 + x^3,
例如 如果你想计算出 x^2+x^3 的反导数
then you would work out the first answer, which is x^3/3, the second one, x^4/4,
那么你就会计算出第一个答案 即 x^3/3 第二个答案 x^4/4
and then you add the constant c and you’re done.
然后你加上常量 c 就可以了
That’s the way to find the antiderivatives of a sum.
这就是寻找一个和的反导数的方法
Next if you have a difference,
接下来如果你有一个差
then you can simply work out the antiderivatives of each term
那么你可以简单地计算出每个项的反导数
and then find the difference of those antiderivatives.
然后找到这些反导数的差
For example, if you have 5 – x^4,
例如，如果你有 5 - x^4
then the answer is 5x from the 5 and x^5/5 from the x^4.
那么答案是 5x 由 5 和 x^5/5由x^4 组成
That’s the proof that the answer is correct.
这就是答案正确的证明
These rules correspond to the sum and difference laws for differentiation.
这些规则对应于微分的和差法则
We also have a constant multiple law which says that
我们还有一个恒定的倍数法则 它说的是
if you want to work out the antiderivative of kF'[x], then the answer is kF[x] + C.
如果你想计算出 kF'[x] 的反导数 那么答案是 kF[x]+C
Now in just the same way, there are rules for products and quotients,
现在以同样的方式 产品和商也有规则
but they are much harder to use.
但它们的使用难度更大
Okay. How about trig functions?
好吧 那三角函数呢
Let’s say you have the trig functions over here, the six basic ones—
比如说 你有三角函数 六个基本函数
sine, cosine, tangent, secant, cosecant and cotangent—and those are the derivatives.
正弦、余弦、正切、正割、余割和余切 这些都是导数。
For example, if you want to work out the antiderivative of Sec[x]Tan[x].
例如 如果你想求出 Sec[x]Tan[x] 的反导数
You look back over there, and the answer is Sec[x] from here plus the constant C.
你回头看那边 答案是这里的 Sec[x] 加上常数 C
Here is a table of all those antiderivatives.
下面是所有这些反面教材的表格
The antiderivative of cosine is sine, et cetera.
余弦的反义词是正弦 等等
Now of course in each case, you must put the +C at the end,
当然 在每一种情况下 你必须在最后加上 +C
but I haven’t done that in this table.
但我还没有在这个表格里做过
Okay. As an example of how we can apply all this knowledge,
好吧 我知道了 作为一个例子 我们如何应用这些知识
let’s try and find the general antiderivative of the function f over here.
让我们试着在这里找到函数 f 的一般反导数
You have a sum over here, so you can apply the sum rule,
你在这边有一个和 所以你可以运用和规则
and you see that the antiderivative of 3Sin[x] is –3Cos[x] + C.
你可以看到 3Sin[x] 的反演是 -3Cos[x]+C
Let’s check that. That’s correct.
让我们检查一下 是的 没错
Then what you do is you break up this over here into two terms by writing it as a difference.
那么你要做的就是把这边的这个拆成两个项做差
You simply separate out the terms and then you work out the antiderivative separately,
你只要把这些项分开 然后再分别计算出反导数
so you get 4x^5/5 + C for the first term,
所以你得到 4x^5/5+C 的第一项
and –x^–1/2 has the antiderivative –x^1/2/(–1/2) + C.
而 -x^-1/2 有反推式 -x^1/2/(-1/2)+C
The complete antiderivative is over here
完整的反导数在这里
Here’s a check that each part is correct
下面检查一下各部分是否正确
so you can find the complete answer for the whole expression
所以你可以找到整个表达式的完整答案
by simply adding things together,
通过简单地将东西加在一起
and here’s a verification that everything is correct.
而这里的验证 一切都正确
In general, you will need to combine rules to get the answer for the full problem.
一般来说 你需要结合规则 才能得到全部问题的答案
Okay. These antiderivatives are very useful for solving differential equations.
好了 这些反导数对解决微分方程非常有用 这些反导数对解决微分方程非常有用
What are these? They are equations that involve derivatives.
这些是什么 它们是涉及导数的方程
Now in general, it’s pretty difficult to solve differential equations,
现在一般来说 解微分方程是相当困难的
but one can solve some simple ones with what we’ve learned so far.
但可以用我们目前所学的知识解决一些简单的
For example, if I said solve the equation f'[x] = x√x where f[1] = 3,
例如，如果我说解方程 f'[x]=x√x 其中f[1]=3
then what you would do is you would first work out the antiderivative over here,
那么你要做的是你会先计算出这里的反导数
and then we’ll apply the condition f[1] = 3.
然后我们将应用条件 f[1]=3
The antiderivative in this case is 2x^(5/2)/5 + C.
在这种情况下，反导数是 2x^(5/2)/5+C
Let’s check that. Then you want to find the value of C.
我们来检查一下 然后你想找到 C 的值
What you do is you plug in x = 1 in the equation—remember that f[1] is 3—
你要做的是在方程中插入 x=1 记住 f[1] 是 3-
and work out the value of C. You have that the required solution,
并计算出 C 的值 你有所需的解
the particular solution, is (2x^(5/2) + 13)/5.
具体的解 是 (2x^(5/2)+13)/5
Now of course we have a very nice function in the Wolfram Language called DSolve
当然 在Wolfram语言中我们有一个非常好的函数 叫做DSolve。
which will do that for you automatically, but before that,
会自动帮你完成 但在此之前
let’s just clear the function f because we defined it earlier on and call DSolve,
我们只需清除函数 f 因为我们在前面定义了它 然后调用 DSolve
and you get back just the same answer.
而你却得到同样的答案
That’s the differential equation, that’s the condition f[1] = 3,
这就是微分方程 这就是条件 f[1]=3
and you simply want to solve for f[x] with variable x,
而你只想求解 f[x] 与变量 x
and DSolve will do that for you quite easily.
而 DSolve 可以很容易地帮你完成这个任务
Okay. A slightly harder example.
好吧 一个稍微难一点的例子
Let’s take a second-order differential equation where you have a second derivative over here.
让我们来看看一个二阶微分方程 你在这里有一个二次导数
You’re given f'' and two conditions, f[0] and f[1].
给你 f'' 和两个条件 f[0] 和 f[1]
What you do is you first of all work out f'[x] by one antiderivative computation,
你要做的是 首先通过一次反推演计算算出 f'[x]
and you get 4x^3 – 3x^2 – 8x + C. Let’s check that.
而你得到 4x^3 - 3x^2 - 8x+C 我们来检查一下
Then what you do is you start with the expression over here
然后 你要做的是 你开始与表达式在这里
and work out its antiderivative and you get another answer, so the answer over here.
并计算出它的反导数 你会得到另一个答案 所以答案在这里
Okay. Then you want to solve for C and D,
好吧 那么你要解决 C 和 D
so you take the expression from there and you plug in the values given to you,
所以你从那里获取表达式 然后插入给你的值
and you find the value of c is 5 and the value of d is 1.
而你发现 c 的值是 5 d 的值是 1
You’ve worked out a particular solution as shown over here.
你已经想出了一个特别的解决方案 如图所示
Of course, you can do all that with DSolve automatically
当然 您也可以通过 DSolve 自动完成这些工作
and get back the same answer as you did by hand.
并得到和你手工操作一样的答案
Okay. Now an application to physics.
好了 现在是物理学的应用 现在是物理学的应用
Let’s say you’re given the acceleration of a particle as 6t^2 – 10,
假设给你一个粒子的加速度为 6t^2 - 10
and you’re given that the velocity at time t[0] = –4 and the position at that time is 3.
而你给出的是时间的速度 t[0] =-4 此时的位置是 3
You want to work out the position function.
你想锻炼位置函数
For the first step, you work out the velocity by antidifferentiation as 2t^3 – 10t + C.
第一步 你通过反差计算出速度为 2t^3-10t+C
Here’s a check for that.
这里有一个检查
Then you work out the position function by one more antidifferentiation.
然后你再通过一个反差来计算出位置函数
Here’s a check for that, and then you apply the given conditions
这里有一个检查 然后你应用给定的条件
because you want to work out C and D over here. So v[0] = –4, s[0] = 3.
因为你要在这里计算出 C 和 D 所以 v[0]=-4 s[0]=3
You plug in those values, and you find that you actually have C goes to –4 and D goes to 3,
你把这些值插进去 你会发现实际上你的 C 会变成 -4 以及 D 会变成 3
so that’s the solution for the problem;
所以这就是解决问题的办法
namely, that you have an expression with t^4/2 – 5t^2 – 4t + 3.
即你有一个表达式为 t^4/2 - 5t^2 - 4t+3
Now you can use the same method but automatically by calling DSolve,
现在你可以使用同样的方法 但要自动调用 DSolve
and you find you get the same answer.
而你发现你得到的答案是一样的
Okay. That brings me to the end of today’s lesson.
好了 今天的课程到此结束 今天的课程到此结束
The main point is that the antiderivative of a function is a function g such that g'[x] = f[x].
主要是函数的反导数是函数 g 使g'[x]=f[x]
Now these antiderivatives come in families.
现在 这些反导数是从他的家族来的
You don’t always just get one;
你并不总是只得到一个
you get lots of them, so you always add an arbitrary constant, +C.
你会得到很多 所以你总是添加一个任意的常数 +C
You can find them by using the usual differentiation rules, but you need to go in reverse.
用一般的区分规则就可以找到它们 但你需要逆向而行
Now the most important application in practice
现在在实践中最重要的应用
is to solve differential equations using these antiderivatives.
就是利用这些反导数来解微分方程
Given a differential equation, you can solve it,
给定一个微分方程 你就可以解决它
but if you’re given some extra conditions,
但如果给你一些额外的条件
you can actually work out a particular solution for that differential equation.
你实际上可以计算出该微分方程的特定解
Finally these antiderivatives are really useful in physics
最后 这些反导数在物理学中真的很有用
when you want to analyze the one-dimensional motion of a particle.
当你想分析一个粒子的一维运动时
With that, we are now ready to go on into what is called integral calculus.
有了这些 我们现在就可以继续进入所谓的积分微积分了
What we’ve done so far is called differential calculus.
到目前为止 我们所做的事情叫做微分计算
In the next lesson, we’ll talk about integral calculus,
下节课我们就来讲讲积分微积分
but before we do that, do make sure you’ve gone through today’s lesson
但在我们这样做之前 请确保你已经通过今天的课程
and you’re ready to take on the next topic, which is integral calculus.
你就可以进行下一个题目了 那就是积分微积分
I’ll stop over here. Thank you very much.
今天就到这里了，非常感谢
翻译 彭彦鸿